CONG MA

6413 15th Ave, Backyard Brooklyn, NY 11219 641-451-0442 • cong.ma0419@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/congma0419

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Versatile software developer specializing in PHP, with approximately 2 years of hands-on experience as a valued team member on client development projects for a leading consulting firm working with global clients. Proven history of contributing at all stages of front-end and back-end design throughout the software development lifecycle. Greatly enjoy Front-end design and development. Excellent knowledge of Angular, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, and other web technologies. Skilled troubleshooter, quickly resolving issues.

CORE COMPETENCIES

PHP Programming • Web Application Development • Database Design & Programming • Requirements Management Systems Analysis • Technology Integration • Testing & Debugging • Troubleshooting & Problem Solving

Languages: PHP, JAVA, VBA

Web: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Angular 2, Bootstrap 3, AJAX, JSON

Databases: MySQL

CMS: Wordpress, Drupal
Web / App Servers: Apache Tomcat, WAMP
Design Patterns: Singleton, Factory Method

SDLC: Waterfall, Agile

Web Services: SoapUI

Tools: Zend Framework, TortoiseSVN, Github, Navicat Premium, Filezilla, FortiClient SSL VPN,

Zend Studio, MyEclipse, NetBeans, Beyond Compare, Jenkins, Sublime Text, Notepad++

Platforms: Windows, Linux

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CAREER NOTE: Completed on-campus studies and currently taking distance education courses to complete a Master's Degree in Computer Science (Available for full-time, W-2 employment). October 2015 to present

DALIAN HI-THINK COMPUTER TECHNOLOGY CORP., Dalian, Liaoning, China • March 2014 - October 2015 Top-ranking IT outsourcing services company working with diverse clientele worldwide; staffs 5,000.

PHP Developer

Team player in the development of web applications and systems, with involvement in front end and back end development, database design and development, and version management. Supported testing and implementation. **Technologies:** Zend Framework, PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, Tortoise SVN.

CONTRACTOR PROJECT

Elevator Selling System, Dalian Hi-Think Computer Technology Corp (March 2014 - October 2015): Designed an elevator sales system for a leading international manufacturer, collecting data from branches in 30 countries and introducing new functionality to address customer needs. Coordinated the functional design, test case development and execution, English-language documentation, and maintenance. Tools include SVN, MySQL, PHP, and Zend framework.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Online Test Conduct System (Production Project), Maharishi University of Management (April 2017 May 2017): Designed and developed a fully functional role based online test conducting system under a short deadline using Java Technologies with Spring MVC and Hibernate frameworks. Developed Functional and Technical Specifications, and a Communications Plan. The System generates a Test dynamically and delivers data securely across the network using Spring Security. The system generates the grades, and provides test results in various sub categories of main technologies. Dynamic reports are generated and saved in .pdf format and appreciated user friendly front end interface. Technologies Used: Core Java, Spring, Hibernate, Restful Web Services, Servlets, JSP,JSON, Java Script, XML, Ajax, JQuery, Jasper, MySQL, Bootstrap, Design Patterns.
- Online Bookstore, Maharishi University of Management (June 2016 July 2016): Created an online bookstore
 with shopping cart and purchase functions, review capability, and book search with sorting by type and price.
 Implemented customizable pagination. Defined multiple user roles for diverse operations, including administrators.
 Used JSF with NetBeans, with data persistence.
- Electronic Dictionary, Maharishi University of Management (April 2016 May 2016): Designed a robust, flexible electronic dictionary with vocabulary search functions and fuzzy search capability. Used JSP with Eclipse for the IDE.
- E-Commerce Platform, Shenyang University of Technology (February 2014 May 2014): Built an online shopping website with several product categories, with involvement in design of modules such as ordering, shopping cart, and user permissions. Implemented back-end database functionality in MySQL. Used Zend Studio as the PHP IDE.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

(In progress via distance education; expected completion June 2018)
Maharishi University of Management, Fairfield, Iowa

Key Courses: Modern Programming Practices, Big Data, Algorithm, Web Application Programming, Web Application Architecture, Software Engineering, Database Systems

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (2014)

Shenyang University of Technology, Liaoning Province, China

Key Courses: Data Structure & Algorithms, Databases Systems, Web Programming, Software Engineering, Java Programming